

VISHWESHWAR KAMMARI

Nationality: Indian (+91) 9390588142 **Date of birth:** 26/06/1993 **Gender:** Male

Email address: vishu2921@gmail.com **№ Whatsapp Messenger:** +91 9390588142

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishweshwar-kammari-365292169/

• Address: HN0: 1-49/3, Near Hanuman Temple Kallakal Village, Manoharabad

Mandal, Medak, Telangana, 502336 Hyderabad (India)

ABOUT ME

Professional AWS Data Engineer with 6+ Years of experience in the IT Industry in Big Data Eco-Systems Hadoop/ Spark ingestion, storage, querying, processing, and analysis of Big Data using cloud platforms(AWS). Worked on RDBMS databases like SQL server, MySQL and Presto. Hands-on experience in Apache Airflow, Python, and Redshift. Worked on AWS services like S3, Glue, Lambda, RedShift, Athena and QuckSight. Worked on RDBMS databases (MySQL/SQL-SERVER/Presto), and Big Data Warehousing. • Extensive experience in Hadoop/Spark Framework and its ecosystems like HDFS, MapReduce, Pig, Sqoop, Hive, Flume, Kafka, HBase, Spark, and HUE. • Worked on various designing phases of the US Healthcare System • Good experience on working with Scala, Java and Python programming languages.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Engineer

Agilon Health [11/10/2021 - Current]

City: Bangalore Country: India

Projects: Agilon Information Model Roles and responsibilites:

- Building data pipelines using ELT process in snowflake creating stored procedures, data cleansing, data transformation, data quality in snowflake
- · Created several data pipelines using Apache Airflow using managed airflow service from AWS
- Worked on Data Modelling for creating several schemas in Agilon Information model.
- Involved in sprint planning, Backlog grooming session using Agile methodology for development.
- Worked on DBT poc for creating data pipelines in snowflake with ELT mechanism.
- Worked on developing snowflake test harness framework using python to perform unit testing.

Senior Software Engineer

ValueMomentum [28/10/2020 – 04/10/2021]

City: Hyderabad Country: India

- Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

PROJECTS: Abacus Connector Factory, Abacus Data Distribution. Roles and responsibilities:

- Worked on AWS services like S3, Glue, Athena, Redshift, EMR for building ETL pipe lines.
- Used Glue Crawlers for parsing the data from several file formats and storing them into Redshift tables.
- Worked on Python libraries like Pandas, NumPy, MatplotLib, Boto3 for Data importing, Cleansing and Transformation operations.
- Written PySpark scripts for doing several transformations after extracting the data from source.
- Created Data Marts with star schema in RedShift and created several KPIs to identify metrics.
- Worked on several file formats like JSON, Parquet, Fixed Width, ORC, CSV, TSV and parsing them to parquet file format for faster performance.

- Worked on scheduling frame works like Apache Airflow for scheduling the Big Data applications and ETL pipelines.
- Implemented dimensional modelling for Data Warehouse and created subject area marts for specific subject area.

Software engineer

Optum Global Solutions [31/10/2016 - 26/10/2020]

City: Hyderabad Country: India

- Business or sector: Human health and social work activities

Projects: Facets Seal, OPRS(Optum Demographics Reconciliation) Roles and responsibilities:

- Performed Data Ingestion from several RDBMS sources to HDFS using Apache Sqoop
- Worked on performance optimization techniques in Spark like Broadcasting, Caching, Serialization for faster processing of data.
- Worked on several file formats like JSON, Parquet, ORC and Avro.
- Worked on Python Libraries like Pandas, MatplotLib, NumPy for Data import, Cleansing and Transformations.
- Worked on Functional programming languages like Scala to implement Spark Framework and make use of Spark Core APIs.
- Written several complex queries to perform bring out the required information from the datasets.
- Worked on Scala for building spark applications for handling huge amount of data.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Technology

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University [24/08/2011 - 16/05/2015]

Address: Hyderabad, 501401 Hyderabad (India)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

Amazon Web Services

AWS Certified Data Analytics Specialty

Amazon Web Services

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Telugu

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C2 SPOKEN INTERACTION C2

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

Python + Spark / Scala / Amazon Web Service (AWS) / Amazon Redshift / Amazon S3 / Amazon Athena / Amazon Lambda / Amazon EMR / Apache Hive / Hadoop (HDFS Hive Sqoop Pig) / Apache Airflow / AWS Kinesis / Apache Flume / Apache KAFKA / Snowflake ETL